A Guide to the Governor Robert Brooke Executive Papers, 1794-1796
Library of Virginia
Additional significant correspondence includes the following: George Clendenin regarding pay & subsistence of a company employed for the defense of Greenbrier & Kanawha (1794 Dec. 20); Paul Carrington accepting a commission as Judge of the General Court (1794 Dec. 18); Andrew Lewis regarding the discharge of the troops under his command on the southwestern frontiers (1794 Dec. 28); Thomas Mathews regarding the admission of two British ship of war into Norfolk (1795 Jan. 9); William Price, Register of the Land Office, regarding two additional clerk (1795 Jan. 15); Edward Carrington regarding the quota of militia called from Gen. Martin's Brigade for the late expeditions against the insurgents (1795 Feb. 8); William Lowther regarding the discharge of scouts & rangers under his command (1795 Feb. 21); Andrew Lewis regarding the settlement of his accounts (1795 March 3); John Steele regarding his tardiness in settling the Western accounts (1795 April 29); Andrew Lewis regarding his application to replace Gen. Tate as paymaster (1795 May 5); Daniel Bedinger responding to charges against him by George Hammond, regarding his deposition of the pilot Thomas Butler (1795 May 26); John Steele regarding the account of Virginia against the United States (1795 June 23); Henry Lee regarding his failure to execute orders by the Lt. Gov. concerning the privateer at Gloucester (1795 July 6); H. Young enclosing a letter from John Page regarding the Unicorn (1795 July 7); John Dawson regarding Indian depredations in Harrison County (1795 Aug. 17); James Monroe, Paris, regarding the statue of Gen. Washington left unfinished while Thomas Jefferson was Minister to France (1795 Aug. 20); William Lowther regarding depredations by Indians in Harrison County (1795 Aug. 24); George Peachey, Mayor of Petersburg regarding two cases of yellow fever brought from Norfolk (1795 Aug. 26); George Clendenin resigning his commission as County Lieutenant for Kanawha County (1795 Nov. 14); Governor Brooke to the Clerk of the Council indicating his temporary absence from office (1795 Dec. 9); Robert Johnson to the Commissioners for Virginia regarding approval of the proceedings of the Commissioners concerning the boundary line between Virginia & Kentucky (1796 Jan. 1); Isaac Shelby, Governor of Kentucky, regarding the boundary line and enclosing an act of the Kentucky Legislature (1796 Feb. 15); William Pennock enclosing a bill of lading from Ve. Homberg & Homberg Freres for three cases containing the marble pedester statue of Gen. Washington and the marble pedestal (1796 April 10); Isaac Shelby enclosing a letter from Alexander Smyth regarding the boundary line between Virginia & Kentucky (1796 May 6); John Hoskins Stone, Governor of Maryland, regarding the extradition of Robert Osborn, a fugitive of justice (1796 June 16); John Dawson regarding obtaining arms for the State of Virginia from Europe (1796 Sept. 11 & 12); Archibald Stuart regarding the agreement with the Kentucky Commissioners on the boundary line (1796 Sept. 27); Houdon regarding his payment for creating a marble statue of Washington (1796 Oct. 8); and Edmund Randolph regarding the case of Fairfax versus the Commonwealth (1796 Oct. 22).
Other noteworthy items include: oath of Robert Brooke by J. Pendleton as Governor (1794 Dec. 1); a list of persons who have migrated to Virginia and given oath to reside therein (1794 Dec. 17); receipts from William Morris, Contractor, for rations to soldiers under the command of Hugh Caperton (1794 Dec. 17); proclamation revoking the previous proclamation of Lt. Gov. James Wood regarding the quarantine of vessels from certain ports (1794 Dec. 19); receipts from Samuel Shepard for the sale of the mace (1794 Dec. 3); order from Will Russell, Clerk of the Court of Directors of the Lunatic Hospital, applying for warrants from the Auditor of Public Accounts (1795 March 31 & 1796 July 12); muster roll of scouts called into service for the protection of Randolph County (1795 May 20); proclamation by the Governor regarding the yellow fever outbreak in the West Indies and the quarantine of vessels from those areas (1795 May 21); petition from French refugees from St. Domingo at Norfolk regarding a plan to send back their negroes (1795 July N.D.); oath issued by John Pendleton to Robert Brooke as Governor (1795 Dec. 1); printed copy of the Treaty of Greenville signed by Timothy Pickering (1795 Dec. 22); proclamation by Lt. Gov. James Wood offering a reward for the capture of John Williford for the murder of Josiah Worrell (1795 Sept. 19); list of commissions of the peace for Southampton County (1796 Feb. 12); list of commissions of the peace for New Kent County (1796 March 4); account of William Hodgson for erecting the statue of Washington & repairing (1796 June 8); appointment of John Robertson by James Wood as Superintendent of Quarantine for Bermuda Hundred & City Point (1796 July 9); bond of Samuel Shepard as Auditor of Public Accounts (1796 Oct. 1); certificate of Samuel Moseley, Mayor of Norfolk, as elector for President & Vice President (1796 Nov. 7); and muster fines of the 22nd Regiment Virginia Militia, Mecklenburg County (1796 Nov. 5).
Arrangement
Arranged chronologically by date of document with undated items arranged to the rear.
Contents List
- Robert Brooke Executive Papers
- 1794
  - December
    - 1-10 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 12-20 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 23-30 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- 1795
  - January
    - 1-9 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 11-30 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - February
    - 1-10 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 11-20 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 21-28 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - March
    - 2-10 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - 11-20 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - 21-31 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - April
    - 1-10 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - 11-20 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - 21-30 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - May
    - 1-10 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - 11-20 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - 21-31 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - June
    - 2-19 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - 21-30 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - July
    - 1-9 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - 11-20 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - 21-31 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - August (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - September (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - October
    - 1-10 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - 11-20 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - 23-31 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - November
    - 1-10 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - 12-20 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - 21-30 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - December
    - 1-10 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - 11-20 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - 22-31 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - County Officers
    - Accomack-Dinwiddie (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Elizabeth City-King William (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Lancaster-Prince George (Box 3, Folder 3)
- 1796
  - January
    - 1-20 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - 21-29 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - February
    - 1-15 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - 18-28 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - March (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - April (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - May
    - 3-20 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - 21-30 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - June (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - July (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - August (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - September (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - October
    - 1-15 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - 18-31 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - November
    - 1-9 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - 12-17 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - 21-25 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Oversized (Clamshell Box)
- 1794
  - Dec. 2 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Dec. 17 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Dec. 17 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Dec. 19 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Dec. 29 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- 1795
  - Jan. 15 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Feb. 10 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - March 21 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - March 31 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - April 27 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - May 5 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - May 9 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - May 14 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - May 14 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - June 19 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - June 24 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - July 6 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - July 7 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - July 15 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - July 18 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Sept. 16 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Oct. 12 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Nov. 21 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Dec. 19 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Dec. 29 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - County Officers - Amelia County (Box 5, Folder 26)
- 1796
  - Jan. 6 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Jan. 22 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - March 14 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - March 31 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - March 31 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - May 20 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - June 6 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - June 16 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - July 30 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Aug. 5 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Aug. 6 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Aug. 20 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Aug. 25 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Sept. 30 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Sept. 30 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Oct. 1 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Oct. 17 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Nov. 7 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Nov. 17 (Box 5, Folder 45)
- Oversized (Newspaper Box)
- 1795
  - July 13 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Dec. 12 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Dec. 20 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- 1796
  - Feb. 12 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - May 6 (Box 6, Folder 5)